Viewers all over the world, I want to say thank you for your time; God’s time is the best.
This is God’s time, thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Hallelujah.
While I listen to some of the confessions... the Bible has said it already - this child is destined
to cause the rise and falling of many; to cause the rise of many who appreciate Him,
who know Him as a Prophet,
but the falling of those who what?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
God has been fighting for me right from the beginning.
This is why you will not hear anything from me.
If you slap me I will just say "OK, thank you".
I know God will fight for me.
You don't fight for God.
Leave the battle for God.
What you say about me, about the ministry...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It is all about Jesus.
Since it is all about Jesus, it is not about me, my effort, my knowledge, my gifts - it is all about Jesus.
He had been fighting for me.
This is it.
It is a pity that a lot might have been deceived.
Many of us here cry when they see the healing going on.
You ask them, "Why are you crying? People are receiving healing and you are crying
instead of jumping and thanking God"
You hear from them that, "I wanted to bring my mammy here. I was deceived and this woman is late now".
You hear different stories just like that.
You just leave your battle for God but it may be very difficult.
You know - at the beginning of the ministry it was so bad - the image out there,
but we just leave the battle for God.
At the beginning, it will be very tough but as time goes on,
at the midway, you will begin to see fruit of your labour.
It’s sweet to leave your battle for God.
Tell your neighbour, "It’s very sweet to leave your battle for God."
You just pray as if all depends on God and begin to work as if all depends on you.
Tell your neighbour.
Pray as if all depends on God but work very hard, as if all depends on you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
At the beginning it will look as if you are surrounded with dark clouds:
you will be doing good and people will be giving other name to it, saying that you are doing bad.
You smile: people say, “You are sad”.
You are happy; people say, “No, there is sorrow!”
They are very good in propaganda.
They have numerous people out there that are very good in propaganda, blackmail, name calling...
and they are trillions.
It is a professional business now to spoil peoples name.
It is a professional job going out to spoil your name, pay people money to destroy your career,
to "paint you black".
It is a professional job now.
In the past, it was not a professional job - you had to hire somebody to do this
but now it is a professional job.
Just leave the battle for God.
Thank God for the blessing God gave us – Emmanuel TV.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
At the beginning, there was nothing like Emmanuel TV.
As God worked here, people would give it a different name there.
But right now, people see it live and direct.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
As I am talking now, people are watching.
They just want to know if it is live.
If somebody tells you, "He said this." you can say, "No, this is what I heard."
This is the battle going on out there now.
The battle now is quite different from the battle in the past.
The battle in the past was, "He said, 'No'" - and they would take it.
But the present battle is:
- "He said 'No'"
People would answer:
- "'No', he said 'Yes'. I was there "
- "He said 'No'"
- "I was there"
It is the fight of Pharisees and Sadducees.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is the argument now.
- "I was watching. I recorded it. I heard him saying 'No'"
-"'No'. He said 'Yes'"
- "No, it was 'No'"
- "No, it was 'Yes'"
This battle is very hot, but they overcome it because it was recorded.
It is just like that.
I know how many of us here were greatly destroyed by it.
Don't give up.
[Amen.]
Tell your neighbour, "Don't give up".
[Don't give up.]
I cannot hear you.
Hold on and keep fighting.
Tell your neighbour, "Don't give up; hold on and keep fighting."
That is a good fight.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You say they lie against you, this is very bad...
This is what they want.
Hold on and keep fighting the good fight and that is the beauty of our journey.
When you are going and something is there to push you back – that is the beauty of the journey.
That will make you value the journey and also make you value the achievement.
By the time you go through and thing about what you have gone through,
what you have encountered – it will make you value whatever you achieve.
When you sit down and think about what you have gone through to achieve what you have achieved...
... escaped death, escaped accident, blackmail, name calling; a lot.
At the end you are there.
You will gorgeously hold that victory and cherish it so much.
There are many people who think they have victory - you see them living a reckless life; clubhouse, smoking,
drinking, going out, when they are very rich.
Doubt that achievement.
That achievement is not going through the right processing.
The right processing means "good, bad - today it is good tomorrow it is bad".
If you go through all this processing to achieve this you will gorgeously cherish the victory.
You can see many marriages today - people say they would quit the marriage, that they are tired...
You ask yourself - maybe they are together because of the outward appearance or qualities?
Probably the lady saw the handsome man, the beauty, the money, fame, popularity -
maybe that's why they came here together as husband and wife.
Anything can break such marriage.
If outward quality is base of coming here together as husband and wife - forget - they will soon what?
Tell me.
They will soon separate.
But if their coming together is a result of something beyond human comprehension - from the heart,
the love from the heart...
You have decided - nothing can break.
The Lord have brought you together - only Him that can what?
Separate you.
Not a situation, not name calling, not someone coming and saying, "Your husband is a criminal.
Don't you know? This is a picture. We caught him."
You say, "No, I'm not interested in the marriage."
Situation will never break a marriage that God brought together.
Challenges will never break a marriage that God brought together.
Trouble will never break a marriage the Lord brought together.
It is not possible.
Even death...
If death comes it cannot separate that marriage.
Can't you hear what Paul said?
What can separate me from the love of God?
Every love of a Christian is love of God.
Because our love sees beyond hatred, trouble, challenges, and condition – beyond.
If trouble comes and you have the love of Christ, that love will still stand.
Trouble will not cause to say, "No, I don't love you any more because you are a criminal."
No, that is not a love of God.
Only God, the Father of love...
This is it.
This is why you keep going around.
Someone from whom you separated some years ago is your friend today.
If you knew that this man would be your saviour, you would not want to separate from him.
But because you have selfish, material, classic love for people...
Look at politics today.
Everywhere, all over the world, Africa, western world, America - all over.
We have seen a man accusing the candidate of being a criminal,
but when the candidate wins the election, the accuser is the one who wants to be the minister of external affairs.
Love of God is the answer to your problem.
Just love and see whether or not you will be healed.
Just love and see whether or not you will be delivered.
You just need love of God; is sees beyond hatred.
If I express the love of God to you,
I will never separate from you because of trouble, unless God says separate.
No matter the trouble, trouble will not make me to quit from that love.
Because if you have a trouble with me and I quit; what about tomorrow - if you are there the one to help me?
What would I do?
I would still come back to you.
This is what is happening today.
People you see as enemies today seem to be your saviours tomorrow.
People keep going back to their former friends.
Your formal political or business friends...
Even in the marriage; people who quitted the marriage - they begin to go back and re-marry.
As for me - I don't know what you are talking about.
You say somebody is bad...
Unless God says the person is bad...
God can use any foolish thing to humble anyone.
What you say - very arrogant...
You just find yourself stealing a property.
By the time you finish stealing the property you ask yourself,
"What pushed me to do this? I have a lot of money. Why should I steal?"
But something has to humble you.
It may be sickness...
When you become so arrogant, that sickness will just come.
What you didn't notice before - you will start to see.
It is to humble you.
After you are humbled the sickness is gone.
Look at what happened to many of you to humble you.
You, who used to count money, you become a beggar now.
Somebody you would never greet is your saviour now.
A lot of things had humbled you.
Many of you say that you would never come to the Synagogue but you sit in the front now.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
And you even ask to record your face.
When we start dancing, some people would be doing...
They want their people to see them at home, that they are here.
And those are people who used to say, "Over my dead body."
Can you see?
We keep eating what we have vomited, like a dog.
We know dog.
When dog vomits it will never eat that.
But we vomit and we eat what we vomit.
This is life.
In our business, you go to places to which you said you would never go.
A man you said you would never talk to - now he is in the position to help you - you go there.
You vomit and you eat your vomit.
This is just life - very embarrassing.
I know this right from the beginning of my life.
When you curse, abuse or lie against me - I will not talk.
I will be looking because I'm afraid that you that hate me now, you may be my saviour tomorrow.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When people start to say, "T.B. Joshua is a devil"...
All sorts of things, you lie against me, whatever you do - I will not talk.
I will be looking at tomorrow.
Not now.
The fear I have is; if you are very bad now, you may be the best man tomorrow.
If I now begin to wrestle and fight with you beyond repair and you are there to help me tomorrow -
how will I approach you?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You - you have done a lot fighting your enemy, those who fight you, trying to do all sort of things...
People insult you, you insult them.
You take them to the court, you sentence them to the prison.
Many husbands of those who are here are in the prison.
Many wives of those who are here are in the prison.
Many house mates of those who are here are imprisoned.
Many of those in here today have imprisoned their staff working with them.
If you look back at what you have done...
Many have imprisoned their saviours tomorrow.
Tell your neighbour, "Many have imprisoned their saviours tomorrow -
because of wrong."
Because of wrong the person has done now, they have imprisoned their saviour.
The person you imprisoned is your saviour tomorrow, and he is in the prison.
Check yourself, your staff - what they have done is bad - we agree.
They might have committed crimes; stealing, destruction in your company, but you sentenced them to death,
or prison - some even to death.
But these are the people God wants to use as the saviour for you tomorrow,
no matter how bad the person is now.
Tomorrow is something you don't understand, a mystery you don't understand.
But because you claim your right, "Oh no, this man insulted me, embarrassed me, stole my property" -
you sentence him to prison.
The same man is your saviour tomorrow.
You will miss a saviour tomorrow, but he is there.
It could be a saviour to your children tomorrow.
This is why the Bible says, “Forgive those who have trespassed against us…”
You want to say, "Father, forgive me".
Have you forgiven those who have wronged you?
You say, "Forgive us, as we forgive those who have what"?
[Wronged us.]
This is what is meant.
Father, forgive us, as we forgive those who have...
The condition is: you have to forgive them before He can forgive you.
The condition is: these people that are wrong today...
Even the Bible in the book of Galatians said it:
if you have caught someone in act of sin or mistake...
You caught somebody stealing - it says that you should restore that person gently.
To restore somebody back is to counsel the person, to talk to the person, not to judge the person.
Because if you judge, who will judge you on the last day?
If there is anything I fear most...
If they ask, "T.B. Joshua, what do you fear a lot?"
Tomorrow.
When I say tomorrow I mean "next".
While I am turning I am facing tomorrow.
This is what I mean.
I fear.
I do not fear of what I am looking at now.
I fear what I will see next.
You own now, but God owns our future.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You can say to God, "Please, leave me".
But "next" is there for you to judge the action you display now.
Now, if you see Jesus, you can slap Him, but "next" is there to judge you.
If there is anything I fear - it is "next".
I will not use the word "future", I will say "next".
If there is anything I fear – next.
Tell your neighbour.
[If there is anything I fear – next.]
I fear the "next".
OK, you - I know no fear, but next...
Because of this fear - if you hit me I will just be silent.
Because I don't know; if you are the worst now, maybe you will be there in the future for me.
I have sinned.
Look at Paul, look at Saul...
You have seen your servant in the office; later he becomes a leader.
You have seen someone coming from your village, you received him, housed him, clothed him, took care of him,
and then, before you know it, he becomes a MD of the company,
someone to whom your children run for help.
A little boy or girl who came from the village, and you were there as a father in the city - you receive him
because he is your family.
You ask him where he wants to live.
You begin to use him as your house-mate or house-boy, gardener or whatever...
Before you know it he enters school.
While the time passes, before you know it, he becomes a leader, governor, president...
Now, he is there to help you and your family.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Now, you begin to complain; "Go and meet him. I hosted him when he came to Lagos from the village.
I clothed him, I sent him to school. Go and meet him."
Now, you become a prayer warrior, you pray; "God, this boy - Peter, I hosted him, I received him, I clothed him,
I sent him to school. He is now a millionaire. God, I'm going to meet him now in his office. Whatever I say -
God, enter his heart."
God should enter his heart - when I speak he should listen. I need one million dollars.
He should just sign a cheque for me.
You fast before going there.
You move towards the office, you are about to enter the office...
You know, before meeting a MD or leader there is a protocol to follow.
First, the security will ask you to sit down.
While you sit you start talking to the security agent:
- "How are you?"
- "Fine"
- "It is my son. When he came from the village I was the one who...
... I was the one who hosted him in the 90s..."
And the security agent is surprised, "You hosted him?"
If you have some wonderful pictures when he was very small, you show them explaining,
"This is him, this is me."
It is true.
The agent would haste to inform others.
He informs senior security officers, "Close family member wants to see the governor".
They will inform the senior adviser to the governor - because they work by directives.
The adviser would react, "Please! What is your name? You are sacked. What family member?"
We are talking of protocol - do you imagine bringing somebody from the village?
Would this person be able to see the governor?
These are the stories.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Fear next.
Tell your neighbour.
[Fear next.]
I cannot hear you.
If you don't fear next you will finish telling stories.
Tell your neighbour, "If you don't fear next you will end up telling stories."
If some people, they are telling stories...
Many of us here have time to tell stories of the president, the secretary general,
how you started schooling and he was junior to you, how you used to help him, how you were the first student,
how you were senior...
People would be listening.
By the time you finish they would...
I don't want to tell stories.
I fear next.
When I see a little boy coming my way, I don't want to know his background.
Whether he is rich or poor... because God is always on the side of those poor.
God is always on the side of those who have nothing.
Those little children when I see them - I am always careful.
I need to tell you people why I am always careful about the next.
Do you know that Jesus can come as a person to test your faith, to see how strong you are?
It could happen even here in the church.
He would just come and put on the rug, the kind of thing you don't expect people to wear coming to the church.
He would start His test from the security.
"Please, help me. I want to worship."
If security agents are not in the Spirit, they would say, "Please! Before I open my eyes... Find your way!"
And we are here for Jesus.
The same Jesus we are here for, is the same we are chasing out.
What next to come?
If you chase away Jesus, what next?
Many of us...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You are in the posh car, driving...
Somebody would just come and said, "Please, I have not eaten since morning. Help me."
You look at the person...
You don't know that the Saviour you are calling is the one that is asking you for help.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You don't know.
You will say, "How the Saviour of the world could come just like that?" No!
He has no beginning, He has no end.
After the prayer and any other thing we are here for, there is a time to test your faith.
This test will make 90% of the mark, and what is here will make only 10% of the mark.
That is why...
Whatever we receive needs to be examined by tests.
Just after leaving here it is a time to test your faith.
Time of tests starts even here.
That is the beauty.
Nothing comes for nothing; nothing comes by chance.
You should be ready for tests that will test your faith.
Do you mean what you are saying?
Do you mean what you are doing?
Do you mean what you confess?
"Lord Jesus, I am a sinner, come in to my live, enter my soul, wash me with your precious blood..."
Do you actually mean it?
A test will confirm whether you mean what you are confessing.
Look at the gentleman here; he came with walking sticks for healing.
I don't know where he is coming from.
He has passed through many churches, but he is here.
The question I used to ask myself, "Why here?"
This is to test my faith.
Not that I'm superior or better than any other person but he came to test my faith.
For my faith to be tested - I need to be very just.
To be just is to do what Christ wants us to do.
Prayer - we are given this grace to pray freely and you are to pray for him freely.
And you have to thank him, greet him, and give him a kiss.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Pray for him, ask him if he is OK, call the evangelist to take care of him.
If you need money...
Maybe he has spent all his money.
Now, he is here.
If you don't help him financially he may return to the world and whatever you have done for him is a waste.
It is somebody who had spent all his money on this sickness and is here.
And now he is cured.
Now, he needs to eat, to go home, and he becomes a beggar again.
This is another temptation.
That could lead him to loosing his miracle.
So, please - ask him if he needs transport.
Let him come again tomorrow, let us intervene.
He has to keep fighting a good fight.
We need to do whatever he needs to support him.
He should not be giving us money.
Him giving his money being sick, he is giving us his own sickness.
And I don't want sickness.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If this man has money and you tell him to pay 100 000 Naira - he will give you immediately
but that money is not from his heart.
He is giving you on condition: "Heal me - receive money".
This is an exchange of the sickness.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
He will bring it but it is not from his heart.
That is not an offering.
He would give me on condition that he would be healed.
It is like exchanging sickness with money.
He will give the money and the sickness.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You know the reason why I will not collect money directly from you - that is my principle.
I will not collect anything directly from you.
If you want to give just drop it in the box or anywhere.
And I don't want to hear what you gave.
You give to God.
These evil people - they like rewards, honor, to hear "thank you".
They want to be noticed and known.
If you don't give them that chance to be introduced to the general overseer, they will not give.
Their reward is to be noticed and known.
Their reward is not the Kingdom of God.
They don't know where they go.
Their reward is in this world - to be noticed, honoured, and respected.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There is a way we can eradicate corruption in the places of worship, in the church.
It is easy to eradicate this.
General overseer does not have any links with people that want to give money.
He doesn't even know them, or allow anyone to mention about it.
... they will not give you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Yes, they will not give you.
If my money comes from corruption, killing, stealing or destruction - the person I will give it to must honor me.
This is my reward because God will not honor me.
If God will not honor me, you, whom I give to, should honor me and respect my position.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
But you, whom God inspired to give...
... you will not even want man of God to know about it.
If God inspired you to give, you would not want man of God to know this.
Because you will not want to hear "thank you" from him.
That "thank you" from the man of God will affect the blessing of God.
[Amen]
The SCOAN Sunday Service
God is the Rewarder.
He rewards man of God himself, He rewards you.
So, the reward of man of God is meaningless if truly God inspired you.
This is the reason why it is difficult for you to see me "one on one".
I always pray to know what a person wants to see me for.
Does this person want to give me money, or a gift?
I try to see what this person wants to give me.
If you give me and I reject it - you will not like it.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Where are we going?
The way out for you is so simple and you are destined to be great.
No, I'm telling you.
It is that greatness that is pushing you up and down, "Go this way".
If you were not destined to be great you would not come here.
But you have not achieved that greatness.
Something is telling you that you are a head and not tail.
If you are not a head yet - that is why you are here.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There are many of you – God just wants you to know what is to suffer
because He wants to take you high.
If you know what it means to suffer and you achieve that greatness,
you will take care of those who are suffering.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The greatest challenge in the world we are facing today is simple.
99% of those who occupy exalted positions, who are rich, famous all over the world -
they don't know what it means to suffer.
That is why they cannot take care of those who are suffering.
It is a disaster.
I think it is the reason why it is so difficult now to reach the position of honor, fame, exaltation...
The Lord knows that people need to know what does it mean to sleep in the dark,
to be sick, to be at the point of death, to face hardship, to be lonely, to be called names, to be in prison
to go through tribulation, before you achieve the position of honor.
If you are there and you experienced sickness, poverty, imprisonment, to be lied against -
and you are in the position of honor you want to take care, you want to help people, because you remember
being in the same position.
When you see somebody suffering, and you have so many, you are in the high position
and you have gone through it - you would say, "Oh my God".
You would be crying everyday, you would want to help.
Even the governor, minister, president - they should visit prisoners at least once in a month.
There are many people who are there being held innocent.
And they have been sentenced for a life in a prison.
People put stories together and they imprison the innocent for life.
They lie against them.
You, as a governor, visit the prison and ask them to give you a table there and you tell them that
you want to see the people that have been sentenced for life in prison.
Even if there are hundred of them you would see them "one on one".
You would ask, what happened, what were their case about, why they were sentenced for a life in a prison.
If you listen to some of their stories and follow it up, you would establish the truth and save them.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Many are being held innocent.
This is why many of us face failures in business despite your efforts.
Opportunities are given to others instead you.
It does not mean that God is not aware.
God wants you to go through disappointment that you may know what it means to be disappointed.
When you become rich, you can know what disappointed people feel.
It is not too late.
God wants you to be strong.
It is good to be strong before you become victorious.
I thank God that I passed through all this.
Yes.
Even without regard to my age, but it is good.
You will trust in authority not majority if you pass through all this.
You always trust in majority.
To trust a majority is to trust so much in people to help you,
instead of running to your prayer room, running to God.
God will be the one to tell you, "Go to this person, go to that person..."
God will choose those who will support you.
It is not you who will choose them.
He has his people and He knows His people, and He will show you His people.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You need a counsel, something you take home, something you meditate over.
You need it.
Look at our champions all over the world.
How many of them run the race to the end?
Our champions today - they end bad.
Many of the richest people all over the world end bad.
They often end as poor people, before they die.
Champions in all areas of life - they don't end well.
Why?
The beginner is not the owner but the finisher.
Champions don't end well.
God doesn't want your journey to go like that.
He wants you to end well.
To end well is to experience trials, disappointments, appointments, failures, successes -
you have to pass through all this.
Be strong!
You have to be strong.
Forget about your age.
If you are getting too old, God can add to your age.
You will achieve what He wants you to achieve.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You look at your age, "I'm getting old now. I have not achieved this or that.
Am I going to achieve it at the age of 70?"
Forget about that.
Which kind of age are you talking about?
There are two ages.
You know one age, the other age you don't know.
God knows.
The other age is the age at which you will leave this world.
The age you know cannot tell you when you will leave this world.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There are two ages; the one you know - the one that started when you were born,
the other age is with God - when you will leave this world.
Any time you sit down and think about your age, remember about the other age that you don't know.
That one is more important.
What you will leave behind, if today is your last day on earth...
What you will leave behind is more important than what you claim to achieve.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Think about that other age.
Two ages.
God owns age - and you are celebrating your own age, but the God's own age is there.
So, just be happy and give thanks to God.
No matter what happened, no matter what comes - Jesus is good all the time.
It is good for you.
You just have to start as a new baby.
There are many things you don't know - like this relationship I'm talking about.
Little thing, fight, disagreement, lie; hey, today I quit, it is no longer my friend - no.
Situation should not break your relationship.
Challenges should not break a relationship.
Conditions should not break a relationship - let God Himself quit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
God Himself is a Father of relationships - he should be the one to decide whether to quit.
Many of them are leaders all over the world.
You run to them saying that you knew them from the beginning.
They are leaders now.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You look at names of people managing the bank - you will be surprised that you know them.
Some of them own companies.
God's will does things in mysterious ways - you have to be very careful.
If at your work place they tell that they demote you - don't leave because of this reason.
You need to ask God for the direction.
They may demote you, they may put the junior one at the superior position, they can cut a half of your salary -
don't quit because of that.
You need to examine what has happened.
God can use any foolish thing - these are the bad things - to try to address you.
And when you are given a sack letter, although you did nothing wrong, just smile - God is still saying something.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What can God say through a sack letter?
Yes, remember about those who are still alive and those who already died.
If you ask the richest people in the world, owners of big companies,
what let them to establish their own companies - it was a sack letter given to them.
If they were not given the sack letter, they would have not discovered themselves.
I have a good example.
Emmanuel TV is the first "satellite" here...
I want to give you a story.
When I was airing my program on one of the national channels...
Because of me they did not allow showing miracles in Nigeria.
Just because of me alone.
And they told me that showing miracles was not allowed.
I asked them how should I arrange my program.
They said, "Just talk. Jesus is love."
I removed all my programs from that TV station and I went to the mountain to pray.
God said, "Yes, I am aware. I want you to discover yourself. I will give you a channel called Emmanuel TV."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Emmanuel TV.
The name Emmanuel is too long - that is what I said to myself.
I purposely changed it to SCOAN TV.
I said Emmanuel TV was too long - but I heard it clearly - Emmanuel TV.
I said that this Emmanuel TV name would be too long.
I would need to write the whole name - Emmanuel TV.
I see other names of stations - they are all 3 or 4 letters, and why mine would be so long?
Can you see?
That is human; and God said "Emmanuel TV".
I went to register the SCOAN TV.
First two months the TV was broadcast with the name "SCOAN TV".
One night, around 2 am I had a vision; the atmosphere changed in the room.
I was warned, "When you wake up change this name to Emmanuel TV".
This is an instruction from God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We started to wrestle.
There was no way we could have done it in Nigeria.
There were no law, no relevant machines, no technologies to do it.
We had to travel to another country.
That is how Emmanuel TV started.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I if hadn't quit, would I have discovered myself?
[No.]
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It is now the most popular Christian channel all over the world.
When that disappointment comes, God is speaking through that to you.
We say, "Don't cry. Don't lament. Don't despair. Don't worry. Even in case of sickness."
I know we have made a lot of mistakes in the past; in marriages, businesses...
Even if you invested in business and the whole thing went bankrupt - it is not enough to quit.
Because bankruptcy is not God.
Only God has the right to say quit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Don't get frustrated at all.
This world is unstable.
Tell your neighbour.
[This world is unstable.]
I cannot hear you.
Yes.
You are walking on unstable ground.
It is unstable.
This is why the Bible says, "In this world there will be trouble. There will be tribulation."
And this is why He said to Peter, "I pray your faith will not fail".
Please!
That shows there are some challenges, situations that will come to shake you because this world is unstable.
I know right.
But you are walking in this world which is unstable.
When something happens to you, you know it is unstable.
What do you expect from a place that is not stable?
You were about to fall.
And if you are not strong enough you will fall.
But if you are strong enough you will get back to balance.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You are not in heaven; you are in this world.
If things are going smoothly, without challenges - it is not good that all problems come in later days
because there will be no much strength in you.
This is what happens to many of you.
You have a brother, a rich man, an authority man that help you...
Your brother is a governor, president, senator, you are very strong, your brother is a rich man,
they keep helping you.
When you are about to fall they will help you.
You can just sit at home making a phone call and getting what you want...
I'm afraid.
I'm afraid the moment they will not be there for you.
I will continue to pray for you.
Take this counsel.
Take it home.
Pass on my greetings to your children, your junior ones, those who are not here.
Say to them, "T.B. Joshua greets them".
[Amen.]
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Help me to greet them with this message.
Now, we find ourselves in the war.
We cannot tell our children, "Go this way" because you do not know which way leads to success.
You are not on the way to success either.
We don't have a road map, and we are showing the road.
Are you a road map?
No.
That is why it is so difficult for our children to follow our instructions.
They look at you, they pity you, they are the ones supporting the house.
They are the ones who counsel you.
Where is the instruction, where is the name momma, where is the name baba?
Father - what is the meaning of father?
The world has turned to that.
Pass my greetings to them and tell them, "Look, Jesus is our father".
[Amen.]
The only legacy you can give to your children is to show them the way to the Lord.
I'm telling you.
Your property is no longer your legacy.
Your wealth is no longer your legacy.
It is like your wealth, property, money, houses... you write a will to give it to them...
It is like you are willing trouble for them.
[Amen.]
I'm saying - those properties, money in the bank, you are very rich, you want to give it to your children -
it is like you are willing trouble for them.
Yes, they only will...
Show them the way of the Lord; let them achieve it themselves.
Way, where is the way?
Where is that way?
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service